Their quest beginneth.
Onward is a family, comedy, adventure film directed by Dan Scanlon.
In a suburban fantasy world, two teenage elf brothers embark on an extraordinary
quest to discover if there is still a little magic left out there.
Ian Lightfoot (voice), played by Tom Holland.
Barley Lightfoot (voice), played by Chris Pratt.
Laurel Lightfoot (voice), played by Julia Louis-Dreyfus.
The Manticore (voice), played by Octavia Spencer.
Officer Colt Bronco (voice), played by Mel Rodriguez.
Wilden Lightfoot (voice), played by Kyle Bornheimer.
Onward is a 2020 American animated urban fantasy adventure film produced by Pixar Animation Studios for Walt Disney
Pictures, and starring the voices of Tom Holland, Chris Pratt, Julia Louis-Dreyfus and Octavia Spencer.
Directed by Dan Scanlon, produced by Kori Rae, and written
by Scanlon, Jason Headley, and Keith Bunin.
The film, set in a suburban fantasy world for the modern day, follows two elf brothers named Ian and Barley Lightfoot (Holland and Pratt, respectively) who
set out on a quest to find an artifact that will temporarily revive their deceased father, Wilden (Kyle Bornheimer) for twenty-four hours.
After directing Monsters University (2013), Scanlon was
encouraged to develop personal stories.
The concept of Onward is inspired by the death of Scanlon's father, who died in a car accident when
Scanlon and his older brother were very young children, and their relationship with each other.
He began to write the story after hearing an audio clip of his father.
The film was announced at D23 Expo in July 2017, with the title being
revealed in December 2018, alongside the voice cast.
The animation team chose to give the film's magic a unique style after studying several
animated films featuring magic in order to fit with its suburban setting.
Development on Onward lasted for six years, on an
approximate between $175–200 million budget.
Composers Mychael and Jeff Danna were hired to compose the film's musical score,
with Brandi Carlile contributing an original song for the film.
Onward premiered at the 70th Berlin International Film Festival on February 21, 2020,
and was theatrically released in the United States on March 6, 2020.
The film received generally positive reviews from critics, but underperformed at the box
office, grossing $141 million worldwide against its between $175–200 million budget.
The COVID-19 pandemic contributed to its financial
shortcomings, due to the widespread closure of theaters.
Like several other films released in the early months of
2020, it found far greater success on VOD.
The film was nominated for Best Animated Feature Film at the
78th Golden Globe Awards and 93rd Academy Awards.
Onward was the last Pixar film released in theaters
worldwide until Lightyear in June 2022.
The film explores themes of elves, magic, dead
father, dead parent, fantasy world.
The tone is lighthearted.